Personally, I've never reported an SQL injection
bug to a bug bounty program, so I was that much
more surprised to see that the sum of bounties
awarded for them isn't really decreasing.
I decided to do the case study and extract
all the disclosed SQL injection reports from
the internet to analyze them. In this video,
I will show you the impact of SQL injection
or how to escalate it to, for example, an RCE or
a file write or simply what to read. I will also
show you the charts of those reports and bounties
per year. Enjoy! So for the impact, I have seven
different metrics here and we'll go through them
one by one and we'll start from the least common,
which was file read or write. In this case, it was
a load file in MySQL. And I'm quite surprised that
this is the only report with this impact because
I also, in the full case study, which is part
of VBR Premium, I also did the breakdown of SQL
engines and MySQL, which is used in this report,
is the most common one, but this was the only
report. And it looked like this. You had the
load file function, which just returned you the
file. So really simple payload. Also the hunter
was quite lucky that the result of the query
was included in the response, but nevertheless,
really, really risky back end. If you have an SQL
injection in a MySQL application, definitely use
the load file. And also the hunter was able to
read, sorry, to write the data into any file,
which possibly could be easily turned into
an RCE. I can't judge by these headers what
technology is being used here, but if this is like
PHP or Java server pages or something like this,
you can easily turn this into an RCE. So this is
a really, really serious bug. So definitely make
sure to test this if you have a MySQL target. The
reason why this is the only one report with this,
one of two probably. One is just people don't
know about this function. The other probably more
likely is that this is not enabled by default,
this function, and developers just rarely use it.
So that's what I would assume. But we'll go to
the next class, which is authentication bypass.
And I had two reports like this. One of them is
here, and we have the case where the most basic
SQL injection payload is being used to bypass the
authentication. This payload, this very payload,
I think is my first ever attack on a web
application. When I was just learning web
security, I think this is like one of the first
labs I've done, so quite sentimental to me.
And I wouldn't really expect this to be present
in a real world application, but apparently
it is. You can also see that this write-up is
quite originally styled, I would say. Quite
strange. There's also an interesting image,
and the system was drunk or something is the
takeaway. And when I do these case studies, I
sometimes go through reports like this where
I kind of, the truth is that I can never verify
a report like this, because if someone says that
the target is redacted, I just have to trust them.
And sometimes I have write-ups like this where I
look at them and I think, is this real? But in
this case, the target is not redacted. It's an
actual thing. It's Django REST framework. And I
checked, it exists. It actually has 26,000 stars.
And I even did go one step further and I wanted
to find the bug, because if it's open source,
I can find the bug. And I didn't spend hours
on it. I spent like 10, 20 minutes on it, and
I didn't see the bug. This framework, since the
very beginning, uses Django's authenticate method.
And as much as I could maybe believe a
simple bug like this would be present in the
not very common framework for Django, I really,
really doubt. I'm pretty sure this bug didn't
exist in Django's authenticate method, which is
probably one of the most commonly used in 2018.
There are regularly SQL injections in Django,
but they are not simple payloads. For example,
I remember this one, because it's the first ever
patch I've reversed. We did a CTF task. It was in
2019. So the bug was already public, but the
payloads weren't public at all. So I had to
reverse the patch, and I remember it very clearly.
And it was quite a complex bug with JSONs,
with some nested property, things like this, and
it was 2019. And I'm pretty sure that in Django,
it wasn't present in 2018. This write-up is from
2018. And also, the write-up here says that he
found 10,000 orders and 800 users' accounts
and 800 employees' accounts on the URL that's
redacted here, but the URL in the beginning
is not redacted, and it is the local host,
which makes perfect sense. If you are testing a
local application, it makes perfect sense that
you test it locally, but then you don't access
customer information. You don't access 10,000
orders unless these orders are yours. And also,
the handler said here $2,000 of reward, which I
don't know. Django now gets bounties from Internet
Bug Bounty Program, which was founded in 2021.
And I also googled this person, their
HackerOne profile. I think I have it
here. And they actually are a real person with
almost 5,000 reputation on HackerOne. So I think
they started reporting real bugs after some
time, but they are not on the leaderboard of
Django or of Internet Bug Bounty. And I say Django
because the website of this framework says that
they handle security by Django security
team. So that's why I'm looking at it. So the
takeaway is that this write-up is, I'm 99% sure
it's fake. I'm happy to be proven otherwise,
DM me on Twitter or on Instagram. If you know
that this is not true, that it is not true that
it's fake. But this is the harsh truth because
here I could verify this. But most of the time,
when write-ups say they are from redacted
program, we have just zero tools to verify this.
And I actually didn't study this. I don't have
time to study every single report like this.
I just, while doing the test run for this video,
I started to think about it and I wanted to dive
a bit deeper. And that's how I found this out.
I hope you don't mind the little off topic.
We'll now come back to our case study
and we'll go to the next category,
which is data write or modifying data. And
we had two reports like this. One of them
has been covered on my channel and not
only has it been covered on my channel,
it's my most watched video with over 200,000
views, even though I recorded it in 2020 with
much worse quality and of pretty much
everything apart from the video topic.
And this vulnerability was in Zoom local
application. It was a local SQL injection,
which meant you didn't inject to the
Zoom database somewhere in Zoom server,
but you injected to the local Zoom client. So the
vector of attack was CSRF-like attack with the
Zoom MTG link to the meeting, which contained
some parameters and those parameters were
vulnerable. The attack itself was also very
interesting with invalid Unicode sequences
and things like that I love. I just love bugs
like this. And the impact was you could write
to the database in the local client. So the
worst thing you could do was modifying settings
for the auto-joining meeting and joining
meetings with the camera turned on. So you
could change someone's meetings and invite them
to a meeting so they would join straight away.
So we could pretty much turn on anyone's camera
on the Zoom call, wherever you wanted. So it was
a really, really interesting bug. One of only two
in the case study, which resulted in modifying
the data. And after writing the data, we
have data read and surprisingly, I only
have seven reports of SQL injection bugs where
hunters actually read data from the database.
You will see later what did other reports read,
but it was quite rare to see an actual like
customer data or a password hash being leaked from
the database. One of these that did read the data
is this one really nice report of SQL injection
in a WordPress plugin, which was only available
in the admin panel, which is normally quite bad
because if you can access admin panel, it's not
really dangerous if you can inject SQL comments
because you have all the access anyway, probably.
But this SQL injection was chained
with cross-site scripting. So
you could attack the admin and your cross-site
scripting payload would send SQL injection
payloads to the backend. So really nice chain.
And especially in this case, it was a blind SQL
injection. Like most of the SQL injections we
have are blind, which means you have to send a
lot of payloads. And normally it is not that big
of a problem because if you're leaking the data,
we don't really care, especially for bug bounty
purpose, when you just want to show the injection,
we don't care if we use 1000 or 10,000 or even
20 or 30,000 requests, if there is no strict rate
limiting. But with chaining it with JavaScript,
it's different because your victim has to stay on
the page with the payload for the whole time,
which really makes you want to be efficient.
In this case, the hunter was able to make
more efficient payload and reduced payloads
from requests from over 2000 to 300 to make the
attack more likely. Also if you're interested in
the technique to optimize your SQL injection
payloads, check out this video I made about
a CTF task from Live Overflow from another
YouTuber, which I solved and I really paid
attention to the effectiveness of my experts.
I think that's a nice video. And this report
is also really nice. Here is the whole payload.
You see quite a lot of code for a normal payload.
And we can see actual data being leaked, which
as I said, is quite rare in case of these bugs.
And it was rewarded $30,000, so quite a
nice reward as well. Next we have RCE with
seven reports. And an example of an RCE we have
here. Of those seven reports, as much as five
were in Microsoft SQL Server, which makes me
think that there is something that developers
need because it's the xpcmdshell function that's
interesting here, and it's turned off by default.
But for some reason, apparently developers
need this and then they either forgot to turn
the configuration off or they actually
use this in the production code or they
just don't think that they will have SQL
injection because who would think this way?
So if you have an SQL injection in the Microsoft
SQL Server, definitely try this out. Here is the
whole payload. So we have something like
this. We have here master.dbo.xpcmdshell.
And then there's the command and no,
I think, no, sorry, the command was
declared earlier. So we just have the ping
here, which is good confirmation of the bug.
And that's good because having an RCE just removes
any reasonable doubt that you deserve a maximum
payout. And now we'll go to two most common
categories. The second most common was
with 27 reports was something
that I called no real impact
because here hunters usually only showed
that the injection is present and they
didn't actually exfiltrate nothing,
not even the version, not even the,
I don't know, the database name. You see a lot
of these are time-based and a lot of them only
showed that the response was delayed. So they
had the sleep function like here, sleep time
means sleep for 10 seconds. So the response
is delayed and it does prove that this SQL
injection is there. I'm actually, I'm definitely
not saying that there's anything wrong with this,
but it just not exfiltrating any data and it
basically works well enough. In most cases,
it doesn't have to be time-based. For
example, here we have the if expression,
which changes based on some statement. Here we
just have one equals two, which is always false.
And based on the response length, the hunter could
determine if the condition was true or false.
So again, not exfiltrating any data, just
showing that the database query was processed.
And the average bounty here was $920. But in the
most common category, which was reading database
metadata, it's $1,500. And so it's 50% increase
of the average bounty for pretty much nothing.
Because this category, reading database metadata,
means that the hunters read something which wasn't
confidential. So previously we had the category
read data, where you would read customer data,
password, hash, something like this. The best
case scenario, basically, apart from RCEs and
everything. And this is the second best. If
you, for some reason, are unable to do that,
or you don't want to read the data because
you're afraid the customer won't like it,
you should read some metadata about the
database. For example, database name,
database version. Here we have one of the very few
examples where hunters could see in the response
the result of the query. Normally, this is not
possible. And here, just payload from the path was
returned here, which is really interesting. I'd
like to see the code behind this functionality.
So here we have database version. So nothing
really sensitive, but enough to prove the SQL
injection is there. But sometimes it was really
not much. For example, here the hunter extracted
the length of the database name. So basically
length of the database function call, which was
11. And determined this on some logical condition
as well, because there is no time delay here.
Here you just have the first digit of the version.
And it's basically enough to prove that the
injection is there. And yeah, it doesn't feel like
much more than, I don't know, showing the delay.
But we can see on the average bounty that it's
just better. And if we see like reading real data,
looking at the average here doesn't make sense
because there is a mass write-up from Apple,
which skews the data. But the rest is 30K, 10K,
4.5K, 3K, 1.5K, and $200. So it's definitely more
than those ones. So if you have an SQL injection,
invest at least this additional time into reading
some data or at least leading some metadata from
the database. Don't just report the time delay. As
promised, charts of reports and bounties by year.
We can see that the number of reports is actually
quite consistent. If we take the 2020 year away,
I don't know what's the reason behind there being
more reports in 2020. And in 2022, we don't
see many more reports than in previous years,
but we see a lot more bounties being awarded. So
this is very interesting. It also shows me that
SQL injection is not dead and I should maybe look
for it sometime. But also, as always, relying on
disclosed reports is not perfect because it's
only a small portion of all the reports being
disclosed. So it's not the perfect statistic, but
it's the best we have. If you've learned something
new from this small part of the case study, I'm
sure that you will enjoy the full version in BBR
Premium Archive. The link is in the description.
And if you want to see another free video,
I suggest you this one about account takeover
case study, where I took a look at over 1.3
million dollars worth of bug bounty reports.
For now, thank you for watching and goodbye.